

Human resources generalist with 8 years of experience in HR, including hiring and terminating, disciplining employees and helping department managers improve employee performance. Worked with labor unions to negotiate compensation packages for workers. Organized new hire training initiatives as well as ongoing training to adhere to workplace safety standards. Worked with OSHA to ensure that all safety regulations are followed.

Professional Experience

Human Resources Manager

Jim's Widget Factory, Plano, TX | January 2016-Present

- Implement effective company policies to ensure that all practices comply with labor and employment regulations
- Increased employee retention rates by managing workpl ace satisfaction to an over 90% success rate by creating and maintaining a positive work environment
- Develop targeted outreach practices to increase minority recruitment and ensure compliance with affirmative action policies
- Monitor scheduled in and out times as well as employee breaks to ensure that proper employment laws are met

Human Resources Generalist

Citibank, Houston, TX | May 2014-December 2015

- AsSi sted with h i ri n g a nd recruit i ng, atte nded a 11 h i ri n g fa i rs
- Conducted new hire orientation and ongoing training
- Coached department managers to properly discipline and write up employees
- Updated employee records as needed
- Instructed managers on how to complete regular, actionable employee reviews

HR Assistant and Payroll Specialist

yardham Ford Dealership | June 2011- April 2014

- Created employee incentive programs to improve closure rates
- Developed strategies to improve employee satisfaction and increase workplace satisfaction
- Helped reduce employee turnover by 20%
- Oversaw payroll reconciliation for accuracy

4759 Sunnydale Lane, Plano, TX, 75071 em a i l@yo u remai I ,co m (469) 385-2948

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Business The University of Texas at Dallas, September 2007-May 2011

Key Skills

- Detail oriented
- Well-versed in Texas employment law
- Excellent written and oral communication skills
- Develops positive workplace relationships
- Confident in conflict resolution abilities
- · Able to prioritize daily duties
- Proficiency with TimeForce timekeeper software
- · Excel proficient

Certifications

Nati ona I Associ ation of H u man
Resou rces Ce rti fied Tra i n e r